澄心委员会（四）
就这样，伍尔曼在东海岸旅行了近20年，
And so Woolman traveled the East Coast for almost 20 years
与大众分享他觉得是上帝启示
sharing what he felt had been laid upon him
给他的关于奴隶制罪恶的东西。
by the Lord about the evils of slavery.
他因穿着未染色衣服、
He was famous for appearing in
纯白衣服出现于众而闻名，
for wearing undyed clothing, plain white clothing,
因为他认为染色是奴隶劳动的产物。
because the dyned was a product of slave labor.
另外他因晚上出现在农舍而闻名，
And he was famous for showing up at a farmhouse at night
如果他得知饭菜是由奴隶准备的，
and if he learned that the meal had been prepared by
或者是由奴隶端上来的,
or if it was being served by a slave,
他就会在餐桌上禁食，
he would fast while he stayed a table,
所以他的言行都与
so he was utterly consistent with his message
他所传达的信息完全一致。
in both his words and in his actions.
经过20年的这种见证,
And after 20 years of this witnessing,
伍尔曼的言行举止
this mirroring back to this holding up
就如一面镜子
of a mirror where people could,
让人们在吃由奴隶准备
while they were eating the meal
或为其服务的饭菜时可以反观自照。
that a slave had prepared or served.
伍尔曼说的是贵格会的基本信念，
Woolman was speaking of fundamental Quaker beliefs
而不是为见证作证而高谈阔论。
and not haranguing that just witnessing testify.
经过20年的努力，
After 20 years of this,
贵格会教众达成了解放奴隶的共识。
Quakers reached consensus on freeing their slaves.
这个故事的重要意义
Now the important point in this story is
不仅在于伍尔曼在很长一段时间内
not only the way he held up a mirror to
耐心地举起了让人们反观自己的镜子，
people's lives patiently over a long period of time,
而且在于贵格会是美国第一个
but that Quakers were the first religious community
解放奴隶的宗教团体。
in the United States to free their slaves.
而且他们在南北战争爆发前80年就这样做了。
And they did so 80 years before the Civil War was fought.
这个故事让我提出了这样的问题：
It's a story that allows me to ask the question,
“耐心总是那么糟糕吗？”
"Is patiences always such a bad thing?",
慢有时意味着更快，
that's slow sometimes mean faster
如果你所做的事情是针对根源系统的，
if what you're doing is going to the root system
而不是仅仅用症状解来掩盖问题
rather than just putting wallpaper over a problem
并假装已经问题已修复好了。
and pretending that it's fixed.
我认为在组织生活和
I think there's a lot in organizational life
我们的社会生活中，有很多东西
and a lot in our societal life that requires
需要我们有持久的耐心去见证，
that steady patience witnessing that
这可以帮助在我们一些最棘手的问题上
can help create long-lasting and deep-rooted change
创造持久和根深蒂固的变化，
around some of our most intractable issues,
而只是进行投票并尽快完成
whereas just taking a vote and getting it over with
以缓解紧张局势，
as quickly as possible to relieve the tension,
缓解未触及的事情或规定答案
really leaves things untouched or prescribing the answer
并为人们提供解决问题的技术
and giving people the technique that will solve the problem
实际上这种做法并未触及更深层次的事情。
really leaves the deeper things untouched.